
<resources>

    <string-array name="reader_theme_text">
        <item>Light</item>
        <item>Dark</item>
        <item>Parchment</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="theme_text">
        <item>Light</item>
        <item>Dark</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="viewmode_text">
        <item>@string/view_mode_paging</item>
        <item>@string/view_mode_continuous</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="drawer_open" translatable="false">Loading Book</string>
    <string name="drawer_close" translatable="false">Loading Book</string>

    <string name="loading_book">Loading Book</string>
    <string name="Theme_Parchment" translatable="false">Parchment</string>
    <string name="open_file">Open File</string>
    <string name="catalog_home">Home</string>
    <string name="book_toc">TOC</string>
    <string name="search">Search</string>
    <string name="book_rename">Rename</string>
    <string name="book_open">Open</string>
    <string name="book_delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="my_readings">My Readings</string>
    <string name="search_local">Local Search&#8230;</string>
    <string name="search_book">Book Search&#8230;</string>
    <string name="view_mode_continuous">Continuous View</string>
    <string name="view_mode_paging">Paging View</string>

    <string name="pref_rotate_title">Rotate</string>
    <string name="pref_rotate_summary">Allow screen rotate</string>
    <string name="pref_theme_title">Theme</string>
    <string name="pref_storagepath_title">Sync Folder</string>
    <string name="pref_storagepath_summary">No \'Sync Folder\' selected</string>
    <string name="pref_volume_title">Volume Keys Turning</string>
    <string name="pref_volume_summary">Use volume keys to turn pages</string>

    <string name="continue_reading">Continue reading from:</string>
    <string name="sync_conflict">Sync conflict</string>
    <string name="view_mode">View Mode</string>
    <string name="image_original_size">Original Size</string>
    <string name="image_fit_to_screen">Fit To Screen</string>
    <string name="image_original_size_all_images">Original Size All Images</string>
    <string name="image_fit_to_screen_all_images">Fit To Screen All Images</string>
    <string name="keep_reading_position">Keep Position</string>
    <string name="add_more_fonts_to">Add more fonts to \'%s\'</string>
    <string name="controls_fullscreen">Fullscreen</string>
    <string name="controls_navigate">Navigate</string>
    <string name="controls_nextpage">Next page</string>
    <string name="controls_prevpage">Previous page</string>
    <string name="controls_brightness">Brightness</string>
    <string name="per_second">/s</string>
    <string name="delete_bookmark">Delete bookmark</string>
    <string name="bookmarks">Bookmarks</string>
    <string name="bookmark_edit">Edit</string>
    <string name="book_font">Font</string>
    <string name="sort_by">Sort By ...</string>
    <string name="sort_by_name_a_z">Name A-Z</string>
    <string name="sort_by_name_z_a">Name Z-A</string>
    <string name="sort_by_added_asc">Added Asc</string>
    <string name="sort_by_added_desc">Added Desc</string>
    <string name="sort_by_opened_asc">Opened Asc</string>
    <string name="sort_by_opened_desc">Opened Desc</string>
    <string name="pref_tts_title">TTS Language</string>




    <string name="app_name">Pellego</string>
    <string name="title_library" translatable="false">Library</string>
    <string name="title_empty_library" translatable="false">Such empty..</string>
    <string name="title_learn_nav">Learn</string>
    <string name="title_learn">Learning Modules</string>
    <string name="title_progress">Progress</string>
    <string name="title_terms_and_conditions">Terms and Conditions</string>
    <string name="title_privacy_policy" translatable="false">Privacy Policy</string>
    <string name="title_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_quiz">Quiz</string>
    <string name="title_quiz_results">Results</string>
    <string name="title_clump_reading">Clump Reading</string>
    <string name="title_meta_guiding">Meta Guiding</string>
    <string name="title_technique">Technique Overview</string>
    <string name="title_reducing_subvocalization">Reducing Subvocalization</string>
    <string name="title_profile">Profile</string>
    <string name="title_sign_out">Sign Out</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open Navigation Drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close Navigation Drawer</string>
    <string name="submodule_popup_dialog">Read the words as they are displayed on the screen. After all the
        words have been displayed, you will be tested on your comprehension. Good luck!</string>
    <string name="quiz_popup_dialog">Now you will be tested on your
        comprehension. Good luck!</string>
    <!--    Module -->
    <string name="title_module_intro">Intro</string>
    <string name="title_module_beginner">Beginner</string>
    <string name="title_module_intermediate">Intermediate</string>
    <string name="title_module_advanced">Advanced</string>
    <string name="descr_module_intro">Learn the benefits</string>
    <string name="descr_module_beginner">Demonstrate basic skills</string>
    <string name="descr_module_intermediate">Show some improvement</string>
    <string name="descr_module_advanced">Prove your mastery</string>

    <!-- RSVP    -->
    <string name="title_rsvp_intro" translatable="false">Rapid Serial Visual Presentation Introduction</string>
    <string name="title_rsvp" translatable="false">Rapid Serial Visual Presentation</string>
    <string name="description_rsvp" translatable="false">Rapid Serial Visual Presentation is a method in which individual words are displayed in rapid succession. The words are fixed to the same
                point on the screen which eliminates the need for saccades. This means your eyes can remain fixed while the words change."</string>

    <string name="content_rsvp_beginner" translatable="false">Fleas are perfectly </string>

    <string name="content_rsvp_beginner0" translatable="false">Fleas are perfectly designed by nature to feast on anything containing blood. Like a shark in the
water or a wolf in the woods, fleas are ideally equipped to do what they do, making them very difficult to
defeat. The bodies of these tiny parasites are extremely hardy and well-suited for their job.
A flea has a very hard exoskeleton, which means the body is covered by a tough, tile-like plate
called a sclerite. Because of these plates, fleas are almost impossible to squish. The exoskeletons of
fleas are also waterproof and shock resistant, and therefore fleas are highly resistant to the sprays and
chemicals used to kill them.
Little spines are attached to this plate. The spines lie flat against the flea’s thin, narrow body as
the flea scurries through an animal’s fur in search of food. However, if anything (like fingers or a selfgrooming pet) tries to pull a flea off through the hair coat, these spines will extend and stick to the fur like
Velcro.
Fleas are some of the best jumpers in the natural world. A flea can jump seven inches, or 150
times its own length, either vertically or horizontally. An equivalent jump for a person would be 555 feet,
the height of the Washington Monument. Fleas can jump 30,000 times in a row without stopping, and they
are able to accelerate through the air at an incredibly high rate—a rate which is over ten times what
humans can withstand in an airplane.
Fleas have very long rear legs with huge thigh muscles and multiple joints. When they get ready
to jump, they fold their long legs up and crouch like a runner on a starting block. Several of their joints
contain a protein called resilin, which helps catapult fleas into the air as they jump, similar to the way a
rubber band provides momentum to a slingshot. Outward facing claws on the bottom of their legs grip
anything they touch when they land.
The adult female flea mates after her first blood meal and begins producing eggs in just 1 to 2
days. One flea can lay up to 50 eggs in one day and over 2,000 in her lifetime. Flea eggs can be seen
with the naked eye, but they are about the size of a grain of salt. Shortly after being laid, the eggs begin
to transform into cocoons. In the cocoon state, fleas are fully developed adults, and will hatch immediately
if conditions are favorable. Fleas can detect warmth, movement, and carbon dioxide in exhaled breath,
and these three factors stimulate them to emerge as new adults. If the flea does not detect appropriate
conditions, it can remain dormant in the cocoon state for extended periods. Under ideal conditions, the
entire life cycle may only take 3 weeks, so in no time at all, pets and homes can become infested.
Because of these characteristics, fleas are intimidating opponents. The best way to control fleas,
therefore, is to take steps to prevent an infestation from ever occurring. </string>
    <string name="question_rsvp_beginner_0" translatable="false">The primary purpose of the passage is to</string>
    <string-array name="answers_rsvp_beginner_0">
        <item>educate the reader about the physical characteristics of fleas</item>
        <item>compare fleas to other members of the animal kingdom</item>
        <item>relate the problems that can result from a flea infestation</item>
        <item>explain why a flea infestation is hard to get rid of</item>
        <item>3</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="question_rsvp_beginner_1" translatable="false">The author’s tone in the passage is best described as</string>
    <string-array name="answers_rsvp_beginner_1">
        <item>concerned</item>
        <item>passionate</item>
        <item>informative</item>
        <item>opinionated</item>
        <item>2</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="question_rsvp_beginner_2" translatable="false">According to the passage, fleas are resistant to sprays and chemicals because they</string>
    <string-array name="answers_rsvp_beginner_2">
        <item>have waterproof sclerites</item>
        <item>are excellent jumpers</item>
        <item>reproduce very rapidly</item>
        <item>can stick to fur like Velcro</item>
        <item>0</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="question_rsvp_beginner_3" translatable="false">According to the passage, which of the following statements is true?</string>
    <string-array name="answers_rsvp_beginner_3">
        <item>Fleas extend their little spines if threatened.</item>
        <item>Fleas have the ability to jump higher than humans</item>
        <item>Humans can jump higher if they consume foods containing resilin. </item>
        <item>The resilin found in fleas is used to make rubber bands.</item>
        <item>0</item>
    </string-array>


    <!--Below string is used for fast testing purposes for RSVP Beginner Submodule -->
    <!--    <string name="content_rsvp_beginner">I was</string>-->
    <string name="content_rsvp_intermediate">Keith recently came back from a trip to Chicago, Illinois. This midwestern metropolis is found along the shore of Lake Michigan. During his visit, Keith spent a lot of time exploring the city to visit important landmarks and monuments.
Keith loves baseball, and he made sure to take a visit to Wrigley Field. Not only did he take a tour of this spectacular stadium, but he also got to watch a Chicago Cubs game. In the stadium, Keith and the other fans cheered for the Cubs. Keith was happy that the Cubs won with a score of 5-4.
Chicago has many historic places to visit. Keith found the Chicago Water Tower impressive as it is one of the few remaining landmarks to have survived the Great Chicago Fire of 1871. Keith also took a walk through Jackson Park, a great outdoor space that hosted the World’s Fair of 1892. The park is great for a leisurely stroll, and it still features some of the original architecture and replicas of monuments that were.
During the last part of his visit, Keith managed to climb the stairs inside of the Willis Tower, a 110-story skyscraper. Despite the challenge of climbing the many flights of stairs, Keith felt that reaching the top was worth the effort. From the rooftop, Keith received a gorgeous view of the city’s skyline with Lake Michigan in the background.</string>
    <string name="content_rsvp_advanced">It goes without saying that humans (mammals identifiable as those that stand upright and are comparatively advanced and capable of detailed thought) have pretty remarkable bodies, given all that theyve accomplished. (Furthermore, an especially intelligent human brain produced this text!) To be sure, humans have overcome predators, disease, and all sorts of other obstacles over thousands of years.
To fully understand and appreciate these accomplishments, lets take at some of the most well-known parts of the human body!
The head, or the spherical body part that contains the brain and rests at the top of the human body, has quite a few individual organs and body parts on it. (It should quickly be mentioned that hair occupies the space on top of the head, and the ears, the organs responsible for hearing, are located on either side of the head.) From top to bottom, the eyebrows, or horizontal strips of hair that can be found above the eye, are the first components of the head. The eyes are below them, and are round, orb-like organs that allow humans to see.
The eyes make way for the nose, or an external (sticking-out) organ that plays an important part in the breathing and bacteria-elimination processes. Below that is the mouth, or a wide, cavernous organ that chews food, removes bacteria, helps with breathing, and more. The mouth contains teeth, or small, white-colored, pointed body parts used to chew food, and the tongue, or a red-colored, boneless organ used to chew food and speak.
The neck is the long body part that connects the head to the chest (the muscular body part that protects the heart and lungs), and the stomach, or the part of the body that contains food and liquid-processing organs, comes below that.
The legs are the long, muscular body parts that allow humans to move from one spot to another and perform a variety of actions. Each leg contains a thigh (a thick, especially muscular body part used to perform strenuous motions; the upper part of the leg) and a calf (thinner, more flexible body part that absorbs the shock associated with movement; the lower part of the leg). Feet can be found at the bottom of legs, and each foot is comprised of five toes, or small appendages that help balance.
Arms are long, powerful body parts that are located on either side of chest, below the shoulders;arms are comprised of biceps (the thicker, more powerful upper portion), and forearms (the thinner, more flexible lower portion). Hands, or small, gripping body parts used for a tremendous number of actions, are at the end of arms. Each hand contains five fingers, or small appendages used to grip objects.
The aforementioned shoulders are rounded body parts that aid arms\' flexibility. One\'s back is found on the opposite side of the stomach, and is a flat section of the body that contains important muscles that\'re intended to protect the lungs and other internal organs, in addition to helping humans perform certain motions and actions.</string>
    <string-array name="intro_rsvp_header">
        <item>What is RSVP?</item>
        <item>What does RSVP allow?</item>
        <item>How does RSVP help?</item>
        <item>How is RSVP utilized?</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="intro_rsvp_content">
        <item>RSVP stands for Rapid Serial Visual Presentation and it
        is a scientific method for studying the timing of vision.</item>
        <item>RSVP allows for the reading of unlimited text in a limited
        position. It allows readers to obtain a maximum reading rate through the ability to adjust
        text size and eliminate space by displaying one item at a time.</item>
        <item>RSVP helps increase reading speed by forcing the reader to stop
        reading out loud inside their head and suppresses the tendency for eyes to backtrack the line
        while reading and searching for the end of the sentence.</item>
        <item>RSVP is being utilized for research in the fields of visual
        impairment, dyslexia, perceptual and cognitive psychology.</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Metaguiding -->
    <string name="title_metaguiding_highlight">Meta-guiding highlight</string>
    <string name="description_metaguiding_highlight">The default highlight color for the meta guiding technique</string>
    <string name="title_metaguiding_intro">Meta Guiding Introduction</string>
    <string name="title_metaguiding">Meta Guiding</string>
    <string name="description_metaguiding">Meta guiding is the visual guiding of the eye using a finger or pointer, such as a pen, in order for the eye to move faster along the length of a passage of text. It involves drawing invisible shapes on a page of text in order to broaden the visual span for speed reading. </string>
    <string name="content_metaguiding_beginner">I just returned from the greatest summer vacation! It was so fantastic, I never wanted it to end. I spent eight days in Paris, France. My best friends, Henry and Steve, went with me. We had a beautiful hotel room in the Latin Quarter, and it wasnt even expensive. We had a balcony with a wonderful view.
    We visited many famous tourist places. My favorite was the Louvre, a well-known museum. I was always interested in art, so that was a special treat for me. The museum is so huge, you could spend weeks there. Henry got tired walking around the museum and said “Enough! I need to take a break and rest.”
    We took lots of breaks and sat in cafes along the river Seine. The French food we ate was delicious. The wines were tasty, too. Steve’s favorite part of the vacation was the hotel breakfast. He said he would be happy if he could eat croissants like those forever. We had so much fun that we’re already talking about our next vacation!</string>
    <string name="content_metaguiding_intermediate">Keith recently came back from a trip to Chicago, Illinois. This midwestern metropolis is found along the shore of Lake Michigan. During his visit, Keith spent a lot of time exploring the city to visit important landmarks and monuments.
Keith loves baseball, and he made sure to take a visit to Wrigley Field. Not only did he take a tour of this spectacular stadium, but he also got to watch a Chicago Cubs game. In the stadium, Keith and the other fans cheered for the Cubs. Keith was happy that the Cubs won with a score of 5-4.
Chicago has many historic places to visit. Keith found the Chicago Water Tower impressive as it is one of the few remaining landmarks to have survived the Great Chicago Fire of 1871. Keith also took a walk through Jackson Park, a great outdoor space that hosted the World’s Fair of 1892. The park is great for a leisurely stroll, and it still features some of the original architecture and replicas of monuments that were. It goes without saying that humans (mammals identifiable as those that stand upright and are comparatively advanced and capable of detailed thought) have pretty remarkable bodies, given all that theyve accomplished. (Furthermore, an especially intelligent human brain produced this text!) To be sure, humans have overcome predators, disease, and all sorts of other obstacles over thousands of years.
To fully understand and appreciate these accomplishments, lets take at some of the most well-known parts of the human body!
</string>
    <string name="content_metaguiding_advanced">It goes without saying that humans (mammals identifiable as those that stand upright and are comparatively advanced and capable of detailed thought) have pretty remarkable bodies, given all that theyve accomplished. (Furthermore, an especially intelligent human brain produced this text!) To be sure, humans have overcome predators, disease, and all sorts of other obstacles over thousands of years.
To fully understand and appreciate these accomplishments, lets take at some of the most well-known parts of the human body!
The head, or the spherical body part that contains the brain and rests at the top of the human body, has quite a few individual organs and body parts on it. (It should quickly be mentioned that hair occupies the space on top of the head, and the ears, the organs responsible for hearing, are located on either side of the head.) From top to bottom, the eyebrows, or horizontal strips of hair that can be found above the eye, are the first components of the head. The eyes are below them, and are round, orb-like organs that allow humans to see.
The eyes make way for the nose, or an external (sticking-out) organ that plays an important part in the breathing and bacteria-elimination processes. Below that is the mouth, or a wide, cavernous organ that chews food, removes bacteria, helps with breathing, and more. The mouth contains teeth, or small, white-colored, pointed body parts used to chew food, and the tongue, or a red-colored, boneless organ used to chew food and speak.
The neck is the long body part that connects the head to the chest (the muscular body part that protects the heart and lungs), and the stomach, or the part of the body that contains food and liquid-processing organs, comes below that.
The legs are the long, muscular body parts that allow humans to move from one spot to another and perform a variety of actions. Each leg contains a thigh (a thick, especially muscular body part used to perform strenuous motions; the upper part of the leg) and a calf (thinner, more flexible body part that absorbs the shock associated with movement; the lower part of the leg). Feet can be found at the bottom of legs, and each foot is comprised of five toes, or small appendages that help balance.
Arms are long, powerful body parts that are located on either side of chest, below the shoulders;arms are comprised of biceps (the thicker, more powerful upper portion), and forearms (the thinner, more flexible lower portion). Hands, or small, gripping body parts used for a tremendous number of actions, are at the end of arms. Each hand contains five fingers, or small appendages used to grip objects.
The aforementioned shoulders are rounded body parts that aid arms\' flexibility. One\'s back is found on the opposite side of the stomach, and is a flat section of the body that contains important muscles that\'re intended to protect the lungs and other internal organs, in addition to helping humans perform certain motions and actions. It goes without saying that humans (mammals identifiable as those that stand upright and are comparatively advanced and capable of detailed thought) have pretty remarkable bodies, given all that theyve accomplished. (Furthermore, an especially intelligent human brain produced this text!) To be sure, humans have overcome predators, disease, and all sorts of other obstacles over thousands of years.
To fully understand and appreciate these accomplishments, lets take at some of the most well-known parts of the human body!
The head, or the spherical body part that contains the brain and rests at the top of the human body, has quite a few individual organs and body parts on it. (It should quickly be mentioned that hair occupies the space on top of the head, and the ears, the organs responsible for hearing, are located on either side of the head.) From top to bottom, the eyebrows, or horizontal strips of hair that can be found above the eye, are the first components of the head. The eyes are below them, and are round, orb-like organs that allow humans to see.
The eyes make way for the nose, or an external (sticking-out) organ that plays an important part in the breathing and bacteria-elimination processes. Below that is the mouth, or a wide, cavernous organ that chews food, removes bacteria, helps with breathing, and more. The mouth contains teeth, or small, white-colored, pointed body parts used to chew food, and the tongue, or a red-colored, boneless organ used to chew food and speak.
The neck is the long body part that connects the head to the chest (the muscular body part that protects the heart and lungs), and the stomach, or the part of the body that contains food and liquid-processing organs, comes below that.
The legs are the long, muscular body parts that allow humans to move from one spot to another and perform a variety of actions. Each leg contains a thigh (a thick, especially muscular body part used to perform strenuous motions; the upper part of the leg) and a calf (thinner, more flexible body part that absorbs the shock associated with movement; the lower part of the leg). Feet can be found at the bottom of legs, and each foot is comprised of five toes, or small appendages that help balance.
Arms are long, powerful body parts that are located on either side of chest, below the shoulders;arms are comprised of biceps (the thicker, more powerful upper portion), and forearms (the thinner, more flexible lower portion). Hands, or small, gripping body parts used for a tremendous number of actions, are at the end of arms. Each hand contains five fingers, or small appendages used to grip objects.
The aforementioned shoulders are rounded body parts that aid arms\' flexibility. One\'s back is found on the opposite side of the stomach, and is a flat section of the body that contains important muscles that\'re intended to protect the lungs and other internal organs, in addition to helping humans perform certain motions and actions.</string>
    <string-array name="intro_metaguiding_header">
        <item>What is Meta Guiding?</item>
        <item>What does Meta Guiding allow?</item>
        <item>How does Meta Guiding help?</item>
        <item>How is Meta Guiding utilized?</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="intro_metaguiding_content">
        <item>Meta guiding stands for Rapid Serial Visual Presentation and it
        is a scientific method for studying the timing of vision.</item>
        <item>Meta guiding allows for the reading of unlimited text in a limited
        position. It allows readers to obtain a maximum reading rate through the ability to adjust
        text size and eliminate space by displaying one item at a time.</item>
        <item>Meta guiding helps increase reading speed by forcing the reader to stop
        reading out loud inside their head and suppresses the tendency for eyes to backtrack the line
        while reading and searching for the end of the sentence.</item>
        <item>Meta guiding is being utilized for research in the fields of visual
        impairment, dyslexia, perceptual and cognitive psychology.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="finish">Finish</string>

    <!--QUIZ STRINGS-->
    <string name="quiz_perfect_score">Perfection!</string>
    <string name="quiz_mediocre_score">Not bad. You passed.</string>
    <string name="quiz_bad_score">Oof. You should try again...</string>
    <string name="quiz_name">Quiz</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_question_one">What city was traveled to for summer vacation?</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_question_two">How long was the summer vacation?</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_question_three">Who were the best friends in this reading?</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_question_four">What was the name of the famous museum in the reading?</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_one_a">Chicago</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_one_b">London</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_one_c">Paris</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_one_d">Bangkok</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_two_a">One week</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_two_b">Eight days</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_two_c">Two weeks</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_two_d">Two months</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_three_a">Henry and Steve</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_three_b">Tim and Mable</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_three_c">Amy and Sheila</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_three_d">Eli and Joanna</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_four_a">The Metropolitan</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_four_b">The Museum of Modern Art</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_four_c">The Acropolis Museum</string>
    <string name="rsvp_beginner_quiz_answer_four_d">The Louvre</string>
    <string name="quiz_results_label">Results</string>

    <!--    Settings    -->
    <string-array name="text_sizes">
        <item>small</item>
        <item>medium</item>
        <item>large</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="text_sizes_entries">
        <item>small</item>
        <item>medium</item>
        <item>large</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_text_size">Text size</string>
    <string name="description_text_size">The default text size displayed in the reader</string>
    <string name="default_text_size">medium</string>
    <string name="title_wpm">WPM</string>
    <string name="description_wpm">The default wpm used in the reader</string>


</resources>
